Wayne Starr

racer159@outlook.com

Profile

2016 Software Engineering graduate of Rochester Institute of Technology with years of leadership experience in the Air Force. Excels at C#, Java, JavaScript, Ruby, Visual Basic, Python, C++, and C application development, and always willing to learn.

Education

Rochester Institute of Technology - 2011-2016

Rochester, NY | 3.85 GPA | Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering | Minor in Military Sciences | Immersion in Arabic

Skills

Programming Languages: C#, Java, JavaScript, Ruby, Visual Basic, Python, C++, C, HTML, CSS

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux, Mac OS X

Development Software: Microsoft Visual Studio, Eclipse, Android Studio, Microsoft Visio

Software: Microsoft Office Suite, Microsoft Power BI

Projects

- Worked in free time on a project with a group of interns to explore people's stories through the use of personable "explorers" that prompt for videos, photos, and audio inputs. This project, called <u>Project Atlas</u>, used lights and sounds driven by a windows phone with additional hardware to help the bots "survive" when out in the world.
- Implemented a new interface for class search and enrollment written in Angular.js as part of the Student IT Office, working with external customers around campus as well as the Information Technology Services department.
- Created a Universal Windows Application for watching live internet television called <u>Kiwi TV</u>. This project was launched in the <u>Windows Store</u> in April of 2016, and has been in development since.

Experience

Defense Innovation Unit Experimental, Mountain View California

Web Developer | September 2016 – Present

- Design, Develop, Test, Deploy, applications for the Defense Innovation Unit Experimental
- Manage and coordinate various project activities using agile methodologies

Student IT Office, Rochester New York

Web Developer | Jan 2014 - May 2014, Sep 2014 - Dec 2014, Jan 2016 - May 2016

- Design, Develop, Test, Deploy, and Maintain enterprise-level web apps for RIT
- Work with a cross-functional team to improve business, development, and design processes

Microsoft, Seattle Washington

Software Developer in Test (Intern) | Jun 2014 – Aug 2014, May 2015 – Aug 2015

- Work with Big Data to discover insights to find ways of improving log scraping for Bing
- Create dynamic reports on data using Excel, and SharePoint

Honors/Activities

- RIT Presidential Scholarship recipient
- 5 years leadership experience in Air Force Reserve Officer Training Corps
- 4 years in Arnold Air Society with 12 months as Area 01 Financial Management Officer
- Placed on Dean's List all academic quarters/semesters
- Enjoy mountain biking, video gaming, snowshoeing, working on cars and off-roading